[
    {
        "question": "أُجِّلَتْ",
        "answer": "are (these) postponed",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 19,
        "tlit": "ujjilat",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لِأَيِّ يَوْمٍ أُجِّلَتْ",
        "rootWord": "أ ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to appoint",
        "waznTlit": "ajjala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "(with) the later ones",
        "pcklId": "152",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ نُتْبِعُهُمُ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "So when",
        "pcklId": "350",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا النُّجُومُ طُمِسَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "351",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا السَّمَاءُ فُرِجَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "352",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْجِبَالُ نُسِفَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "353",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الرُّسُلُ أُقِّتَتْ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "354",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "wa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمُ ارْكَعُوا لَا يَرْكَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْذَنُ",
        "answer": "will it be permitted",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 29,
        "tlit": "yu'dhanu",
        "frequency": "102",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يُؤْذَنُ لَهُمْ فَيَعْتَذِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ذ ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَذِنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to permit",
        "waznTlit": "adhina",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "448",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍa",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ كِفَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُوا",
        "answer": "Eat",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "kulū",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَاشْرَبُوا هَنِيئًا بِمَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to eat, to consume",
        "waznTlit": "akala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُوا",
        "answer": "Eat",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "kulū",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَتَمَتَّعُوا قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to eat, to consume",
        "waznTlit": "akala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "For",
        "pcklId": "722",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ قَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "723",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "724",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ ظِلٍّ ذِي ثَلَاثِ شُعَبٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "answer": "will they believe",
        "pcklId": "545",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "yu'minūna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ حَدِيثٍ بَعْدَهُ يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نُهْلِكِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "and the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "wal-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ جَمَعْنَاكُمْ وَالْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْدَهُ",
        "answer": "after it",
        "pcklId": "206",
        "rootWordId": 139,
        "tlit": "baʿdahu",
        "frequency": "235",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ حَدِيثٍ بَعْدَهُ يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْد",
        "waznEnglish": "was long",
        "waznTlit": "baʿd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُتْبِعُهُمُ",
        "answer": "We follow them up",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "nut'biʿuhumu",
        "frequency": "172",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ نُتْبِعُهُمُ الْآخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "atbaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ثَلَاثِ",
        "answer": "three",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 206,
        "tlit": "thalāthi",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ ظِلٍّ ذِي ثَلَاثِ شُعَبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ثَلَٰث",
        "waznEnglish": "(is the) third",
        "waznTlit": "thalāth",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالُ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibālu",
        "frequency": "41",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْجِبَالُ نُسِفَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "with the criminals",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "bil-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَفْعَلُ بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) criminals",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "muj'rimūna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَتَمَتَّعُوا قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْزِي",
        "answer": "reward",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "najzī",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "Then We placed it",
        "pcklId": "328",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalnāhu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَاهُ فِي قَرَارٍ مَكِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْعَلِ",
        "answer": "We made",
        "pcklId": "329",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "najʿali",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ كِفَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "330",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمَعْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "We have gathered you",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamaʿnākum",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ جَمَعْنَاكُمْ وَالْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to collect",
        "waznTlit": "jamaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جِمَالَتٌ",
        "answer": "camels",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 261,
        "tlit": "jimālatun",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُ جِمَالَتٌ صُفْرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جِمَٰلَت",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) beauty",
        "waznTlit": "jimālat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَدِيثٍ",
        "answer": "statement",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "ḥadīthin",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ حَدِيثٍ بَعْدَهُ يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَدِيث",
        "waznEnglish": "Do you tell them",
        "waznTlit": "ḥadīth",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "answer": "the good-doers",
        "pcklId": "192",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "l-muḥ'sinīna",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَذَٰلِكَ نَجْزِي الْمُحْسِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُحْسِن",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "muḥ'sin",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْيَاءً",
        "answer": "(For the) living",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "aḥyāan",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَحْيَاءً وَأَمْوَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيّ",
        "waznEnglish": "you will live",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayy",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَخْلُقْكُمْ",
        "answer": "We create you",
        "pcklId": "168",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "nakhluqkkum",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَخْلُقْكُمْ مِنْ مَاءٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "will make you know",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرًا",
        "answer": "(the) Reminder",
        "pcklId": "269",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'ran",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُلْقِيَاتِ ذِكْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرُّسُلُ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "468",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-rusulu",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الرُّسُلُ أُقِّتَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَسُول",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "rasūl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمُرْسَلَاتِ",
        "answer": "By the ones sent forth",
        "pcklId": "512",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "wal-mur'salāti",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْمُرْسَلَاتِ عُرْفًا",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُرْسَلَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'salāt",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَوَاسِيَ",
        "answer": "firmly set mountains",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 556,
        "tlit": "rawāsiya",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ر س و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَوَٰسِى",
        "waznEnglish": "He made them firm",
        "waznTlit": "rawāsī",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "ارْكَعُوا",
        "answer": "Bow",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 585,
        "tlit": "ir'kaʿū",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمُ ارْكَعُوا لَا يَرْكَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ك ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْكَعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bow",
        "waznTlit": "yarkaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرْكَعُونَ",
        "answer": "they bow",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 585,
        "tlit": "yarkaʿūna",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمُ ارْكَعُوا لَا يَرْكَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ك ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْكَعُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bow",
        "waznTlit": "yarkaʿu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْمِي",
        "answer": "throws up",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 593,
        "tlit": "tarmī",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا تَرْمِي بِشَرَرٍ كَالْقَصْرِ",
        "rootWord": "ر م ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر م ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to throw, to accuse",
        "waznTlit": "rā mīm yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ",
        "answer": "and We gave you to drink",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 704,
        "tlit": "wa-asqaynākum",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "س ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْقَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give drink",
        "waznTlit": "asqay",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the heaven",
        "pcklId": "344",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا السَّمَاءُ فُرِجَتْ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاشْرَبُوا",
        "answer": "and drink",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 763,
        "tlit": "wa-ish'rabū",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَاشْرَبُوا هَنِيئًا بِمَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرِبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to drink",
        "waznTlit": "shariba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِشَرَرٍ",
        "answer": "sparks",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 767,
        "tlit": "bishararin",
        "frequency": "31",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا تَرْمِي بِشَرَرٍ كَالْقَصْرِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرَر",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) bad",
        "waznTlit": "sharar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شُعَبٍ",
        "answer": "columns",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 777,
        "tlit": "shuʿabin",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ ظِلٍّ ذِي ثَلَاثِ شُعَبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ع ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شُعَب",
        "waznEnglish": "columns",
        "waznTlit": "shuʿab",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَامِخَاتٍ",
        "answer": "lofty",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 795,
        "tlit": "shāmikhātin",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ش م خ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش م خ",
        "waznEnglish": "lofty",
        "waznTlit": "shīn mīm khā",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "answer": "they desire",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 804,
        "tlit": "yashtahūna",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَوَاكِهَ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱشْتَهَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire",
        "waznTlit": "ish'tahat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُفْرٌ",
        "answer": "yellow",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 847,
        "tlit": "ṣuf'run",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَأَنَّهُ جِمَالَتٌ صُفْرٌ",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُفْر",
        "waznEnglish": "yellow",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuf'r",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "انْطَلِقُوا",
        "answer": "Proceed",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 921,
        "tlit": "inṭaliqū",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنطَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to set out, to proceeed, to go forth",
        "waznTlit": "inṭalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "انْطَلِقُوا",
        "answer": "Proceed",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 921,
        "tlit": "inṭaliqū",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ ظِلٍّ ذِي ثَلَاثِ شُعَبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنطَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to set out, to proceeed, to go forth",
        "waznTlit": "inṭalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طُمِسَتْ",
        "answer": "are obliterated",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 924,
        "tlit": "ṭumisat",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا النُّجُومُ طُمِسَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ط م س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ط م س",
        "waznEnglish": "to blind, to destory, to obliterate",
        "waznTlit": "ṭā mīm sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظِلٍّ",
        "answer": "a shadow",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "ẓillin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ ظِلٍّ ذِي ثَلَاثِ شُعَبٍ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظِلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and they were to continue",
        "waznTlit": "ẓill",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظِلَالٍ",
        "answer": "shades",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "ẓilālin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي ظِلَالٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظِلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and they were to continue",
        "waznTlit": "ẓill",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ظَلِيلٍ",
        "answer": "cool shade",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "ẓalīlin",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا ظَلِيلٍ وَلَا يُغْنِي مِنَ اللَّهَبِ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "and they were to continue",
        "waznTlit": "ẓalīl",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَيَعْتَذِرُونَ",
        "answer": "to make excuses",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 969,
        "tlit": "fayaʿtadhirūna",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يُؤْذَنُ لَهُمْ فَيَعْتَذِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَعْتَذِرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make excuse",
        "waznTlit": "yaʿtadhiru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عُذْرًا",
        "answer": "(As) justification",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 969,
        "tlit": "ʿudh'ran",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " عُذْرًا أَوْ نُذْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُذْر",
        "waznEnglish": "make excuse",
        "waznTlit": "ʿudh'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عُرْفًا",
        "answer": "one after another",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 976,
        "tlit": "ʿur'fan",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْمُرْسَلَاتِ عُرْفًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُرْف",
        "waznEnglish": "they recognized",
        "waznTlit": "ʿur'f",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَصْفًا",
        "answer": "violently",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 994,
        "tlit": "ʿaṣfan",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْعَاصِفَاتِ عَصْفًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ص ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَصْف",
        "waznEnglish": "forcefully",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaṣf",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْعَاصِفَاتِ",
        "answer": "And the winds that blow",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 994,
        "tlit": "fal-ʿāṣifāti",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْعَاصِفَاتِ عَصْفًا",
        "rootWord": "ع ص ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰصِفَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "forcefully",
        "waznTlit": "ʿāṣifāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٍ",
        "answer": "known",
        "pcklId": "852",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmin",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ قَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "answer": "do",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "taʿmalūna",
        "frequency": "360",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَاشْرَبُوا هَنِيئًا بِمَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعُيُونٍ",
        "answer": "and springs",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "waʿuyūnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي ظِلَالٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُغْنِي",
        "answer": "availing",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "yugh'nī",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا ظَلِيلٍ وَلَا يُغْنِي مِنَ اللَّهَبِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فُرَاتًا",
        "answer": "sweet",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1113,
        "tlit": "furātan",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف ر ت",
        "waznEnglish": "and sweet",
        "waznTlit": "fā rā tā",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "فُرِجَتْ",
        "answer": "is cleft asunder",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1115,
        "tlit": "furijat",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا السَّمَاءُ فُرِجَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فُرِجَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be cleft asunder",
        "waznTlit": "furijat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَرْقًا",
        "answer": "(by the) Criterion",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1124,
        "tlit": "farqan",
        "frequency": "72",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْفَارِقَاتِ فَرْقًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرْق",
        "waznEnglish": "We parted",
        "waznTlit": "farq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْفَارِقَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who separate",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 1124,
        "tlit": "fal-fāriqāti",
        "frequency": "72",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْفَارِقَاتِ فَرْقًا",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰرِقَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "We parted",
        "waznTlit": "fāriqāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(of) Judgment",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَوْمِ الْفَصْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Judgment",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(of) Judgment",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ جَمَعْنَاكُمْ وَالْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْعَلُ",
        "answer": "We deal",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "nafʿalu",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَفْعَلُ بِالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَوَاكِهَ",
        "answer": "And fruits",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "wafawākiha",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَفَوَاكِهَ مِمَّا يَشْتَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوَٰكِه",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fawākih",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَدَرْنَا",
        "answer": "So We measured",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "faqadarnā",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَدَرْنَا فَنِعْمَ الْقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to restrict, to control, to have power",
        "waznTlit": "qadara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَرٍ",
        "answer": "a period",
        "pcklId": "51",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qadarin",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ قَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qadar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَادِرُونَ",
        "answer": "(are We to) measure",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "l-qādirūna",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَدَرْنَا فَنِعْمَ الْقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَادِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qādir",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرَارٍ",
        "answer": "an abode",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1190,
        "tlit": "qarārin",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَاهُ فِي قَرَارٍ مَكِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرَار",
        "waznEnglish": "and cool",
        "waznTlit": "qarār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْقَصْرِ",
        "answer": "as the fortress",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1205,
        "tlit": "kal-qaṣri",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا تَرْمِي بِشَرَرٍ كَالْقَصْرِ",
        "rootWord": "ق ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَصْر",
        "waznEnglish": "you shorten",
        "waznTlit": "qaṣr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَلِيلًا",
        "answer": "a little",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 1225,
        "tlit": "qalīlan",
        "frequency": "76",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَتَمَتَّعُوا قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) little",
        "waznTlit": "qalīl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قِيلَ",
        "answer": "it is said",
        "pcklId": "1598",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qīla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا قِيلَ لَهُمُ ارْكَعُوا لَا يَرْكَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "answer": "deny",
        "pcklId": "172",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "tukadhibūna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "272",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "273",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "274",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "275",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "276",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "277",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "278",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "279",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "to the deniers",
        "pcklId": "280",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "lil'mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ لِلْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كِفَاتًا",
        "answer": "a receptacle",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1279,
        "tlit": "kifātan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَجْعَلِ الْأَرْضَ كِفَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ف ت",
        "waznEnglish": "a receptacle",
        "waznTlit": "kāf fā tā",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you used to",
        "pcklId": "1335",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " انْطَلِقُوا إِلَىٰ مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تُكَذِّبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "is",
        "pcklId": "1336",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنْ كَانَ لَكُمْ كَيْدٌ فَكِيدُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you used to",
        "pcklId": "1337",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَاشْرَبُوا هَنِيئًا بِمَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكِيدُونِ",
        "answer": "then plan against Me",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1307,
        "tlit": "fakīdūni",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنْ كَانَ لَكُمْ كَيْدٌ فَكِيدُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِيدُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to scheme, to plot, to plan",
        "waznTlit": "kīdu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْدٌ",
        "answer": "a plan",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1307,
        "tlit": "kaydun",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنْ كَانَ لَكُمْ كَيْدٌ فَكِيدُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَيْد",
        "waznEnglish": "scheme against me",
        "waznTlit": "kayd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَالْمُلْقِيَاتِ",
        "answer": "And those who bring down",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "fal-mul'qiyāti",
        "frequency": "146",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَالْمُلْقِيَاتِ ذِكْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُلْقِيَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "they meet",
        "waznTlit": "mul'qiyāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهَبِ",
        "answer": "the flame",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1352,
        "tlit": "l-lahabi",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا ظَلِيلٍ وَلَا يُغْنِي مِنَ اللَّهَبِ",
        "rootWord": "ل ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ه ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the flame",
        "waznTlit": "lām hā bā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَمَتَّعُوا",
        "answer": "and enjoy yourselves",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "watamattaʿū",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَتَمَتَّعُوا قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَتَّعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to enjoy",
        "waznTlit": "tamattaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَكِينٍ",
        "answer": "safe",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1410,
        "tlit": "makīnin",
        "frequency": "18",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَاهُ فِي قَرَارٍ مَكِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ك ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّكِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We had established them",
        "waznTlit": "makīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَهِينٍ",
        "answer": "despicable",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1423,
        "tlit": "mahīnin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَخْلُقْكُمْ مِنْ مَاءٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م ه ن",
        "waznEnglish": "despised",
        "waznTlit": "mīm hā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمْوَاتًا",
        "answer": "and (the) dead",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "wa-amwātan",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَحْيَاءً وَأَمْوَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّيِّت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mayyit",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَاءٍ",
        "answer": "a water",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "māin",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نَخْلُقْكُمْ مِنْ مَاءٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَاءً",
        "answer": "water ",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "māan",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ شَامِخَاتٍ وَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمْ مَاءً فُرَاتًا",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّجُومُ",
        "answer": "the stars",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1444,
        "tlit": "l-nujūmu",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا النُّجُومُ طُمِسَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ج م",
        "waznEnglish": "the stars",
        "waznTlit": "nūn jīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُذْرًا",
        "answer": "warning",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "nudh'ran",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " عُذْرًا أَوْ نُذْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُذْر",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nudh'r",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُسِفَتْ",
        "answer": "are blown away",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1465,
        "tlit": "nusifat",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الْجِبَالُ نُسِفَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ن س ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُسِفَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to scatter, to blow away, to blast",
        "waznTlit": "nusifat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَشْرًا",
        "answer": "far and wide",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "nashran",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّاشِرَاتِ نَشْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَشْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Will spread",
        "waznTlit": "nashr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالنَّاشِرَاتِ",
        "answer": "And the ones that scatter",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "wal-nāshirāti",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّاشِرَاتِ نَشْرًا",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّٰشِرَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "Will spread",
        "waznTlit": "nāshirāt",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْطِقُونَ",
        "answer": "they will speak",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1486,
        "tlit": "yanṭiqūna",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ لَا يَنْطِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَنطِقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to speak",
        "waznTlit": "yanṭiqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَنِعْمَ",
        "answer": "and Best",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "faniʿ'ma",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَقَدَرْنَا فَنِعْمَ الْقَادِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be excellent",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'ma",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُهْلِكِ",
        "answer": "We destroy",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1559,
        "tlit": "nuh'liki",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ نُهْلِكِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "ahlaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "هَنِيئًا",
        "answer": "(in) satisfaction",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1567,
        "tlit": "hanīan",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كُلُوا وَاشْرَبُوا هَنِيئًا بِمَا كُنْتُمْ تَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ن أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ه ن أ",
        "waznEnglish": "(in) satisfaction",
        "waznTlit": "hā nūn hamza",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُوعَدُونَ",
        "answer": "you are promised",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1626,
        "tlit": "tūʿadūna",
        "frequency": "151",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّمَا تُوعَدُونَ لَوَاقِعٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَعَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to promise",
        "waznTlit": "waʿada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُقِّتَتْ",
        "answer": "are gathered to their appointed time",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1635,
        "tlit": "uqqitat",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذَا الرُّسُلُ أُقِّتَتْ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُقِّتَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be gathered to an appointed time",
        "waznTlit": "uqqitat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَوَاقِعٌ",
        "answer": "will surely occur",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "lawāqiʿun",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّمَا تُوعَدُونَ لَوَاقِعٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَاقِع",
        "waznEnglish": "(became) incumbent",
        "waznTlit": "wāqiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "256",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-mutaqīna",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي ظِلَالٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمٍ",
        "answer": "Day",
        "pcklId": "310",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmin",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لِأَيِّ يَوْمٍ أُجِّلَتْ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِيَوْمِ",
        "answer": "For (the) Day",
        "pcklId": "311",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "liyawmi",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَوْمِ الْفَصْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "312",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is) a Day",
        "pcklId": "313",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ لَا يَنْطِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "314",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "77",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا يَوْمُ الْفَصْلِ جَمَعْنَاكُمْ وَالْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]